Max Jacobson

mjacobson7@gmail.com Portfolio: maxjacobson.me 801-234-0170 | Provo, Utah Area

About Me

I'm a Software Engineer with nearly 3 years experience managing all aspects of Software Development. I'm often found coding late into the night working on side projects and learning new technologies. I'm always eager to learn more, and I crave knowledge. I strive to be happy and enjoy what I'm doing, but I'm always looking for ways to improve myself and to improve what I'm working on.

Skills

- lavascript
- Angular JS
- Angular 2+
- Node JS
- Java

- PostgreSQL
- Mongo DB
- JQuery
- HTML5, CSS3, SASS
- Exposure to React

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer

Torch LMS October 2017-Present

Full stack development for a multi-tenant SaaS application with 500k+ users. Integrated the use of timezones in the site for our world-wide customer base. Responsible for a complete redesign of the user assignments page which gave users more flexibility to view tasks assigned to them. Developed a page where supervisors can view their team as well as any of their teams' direct reports. Technologies used: AngularJS, Java (spring), PostgreSQL, AWS

Front End Developer (contract)

Cooper Technology August 2018-Present

Responsible for upgrading aging front-end codebase with a complete UI redesign for agricultural equipment company. Assist with building out a new mobile application as part of a two-man development team using the Ionic framework.

Co-Founder and Lead Developer

SkillAmp October 2017-Present

Conceived, researched, planned, and launched startup in call center industry to help reduce attrition rates and improve customer loyalty. Designed and built multi-tenant SaaS application from the ground up. Regularly collaborating with team members on goal implementation.

Technologies used: Angular 2+, Node JS (express), PostgreSQL

Jr. Software Developer

Torch LMS August 2016 - October 2017

Assisted with overhaul of mobile-responsiveness of application in its entirety. Responsible for deploying code to UAT environment daily. Upgraded in-app video player for a seamless transition for customers. Improved performance with various queries in our PostgreSQL database. Assist the project lead in tracking current project developments and estimating the expected project completion.

Technical Project Manager

Torch LMS December 2015-April 2017

Working at an up-and-coming software company has allowed me to develop many skills and wear many hats. During my tenure, support tickets were reduced by 84%. Demonstrated proficiency in testing web-based systems to identify any performance and quality issues as well as bug tracking. Evaluated new software applications and coordinated with team to address any defects as well as discuss QA concerns. Committed to ensuring that quality standards are upheld to promote optimal customer satisfaction. Facilitated Single-Sign-On and SFTP integrations with clients and ensured a smooth, well-documented implementation.

Desktop Support Analyst

Server Plus January 2015-December 2015

Customer-focused Desktop Support Technician with success in a variety of computer operating systems, applications, and hardware. Consistently one of the top three technicians in regards to not only the number of tickets resolved, but the amount of repeat tickets. Analytical and adept at resolving complex network issues. Critical thinker who addresses customer support issues quickly and who consistently exceeds performance standards. Responsibilities include: Install, configure, test, maintain, monitor, and troubleshoot end user and network hardware, peripheral devices, printing/scanning devices, and mobile devices using a ticketing system.

EDUCATION

Dev Mountain

April 2016 - August 2016

DevMountain is known for teaching developers a practical and adaptive approach to coding and continued learning. While attending boot camp, I quickly expanded my knowledge of specific frameworks and higher-level concepts for effective and scalable development.